<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[warmsheep]]></title>
  <link href="http://warmsheep.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://warmsheep.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-06-12T17:30:29+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://warmsheep.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Warmsheep]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[warmsheep@me.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vi Command]]></title>
    <link href="http://warmsheep.github.com/blog/2012/06/12/vi-command/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-12T17:01:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://warmsheep.github.com/blog/2012/06/12/vi-command</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>以前对于Vi/Vim都是属于非常基础的操作阶段，很笨拙地写文本，用起来实在不方便。后看了同事转载的一篇文章，试着记了一下快捷键，熟悉一点之后，发现vi原来是如此强大。
不过过多的命令也会影响学习的效率，初期我们应该掌握最有效的命令在vi中存活下来。于是整理下，把个人用得最习惯最常用的命令。</p>

<p>我们首先进入vi/vim最基础的操作如何操作，我们使用如下命令可进入编辑模式</p>

<blockquote><p>i  &#8211;在光标当前位置插入（这或许是所有人一开始使用最多的插入命令）</p>

<p>a  &#8211;在光标后一个字符进入插入</p>

<p>o  &#8211;在光标之下新建一行后插入</p>

<p>O  &#8211;在光标之上新建一行后插入</p>

<p>cw  &#8211;替换从光标所在位置后到一个单词结尾的字符并插入</p></blockquote>

<p>无疑i和o的插入模式是最自然，最顺手的两种。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Git translation for chapter 1 [Introduction-介绍]]]></title>
    <link href="http://warmsheep.github.com/blog/2012/06/11/version-control-with-git-chapter-1/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-11T10:08:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://warmsheep.github.com/blog/2012/06/11/version-control-with-git-chapter-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Backgroud-背景</h2>

<blockquote><p>No cautious,creative person starts a project nowadays without a back-up strategy.Because data is ephemeral and can be lost easily&#8211;through an errant code change or a catastrophic disk crash,say&#8211;it is wise to maintain a living archive of all work.</p></blockquote>

<p>不谨慎的话，现在人们启动一个项目并不会创建一个备份策略。因为数据是是短暂的并且很容易丢失——通过不定时的代码修改或者一个灾难性的磁盘crash，他会说&#8211;他会智能的去修复一个现有的档案。</p>

<blockquote><p>For text and code projects,the back-up strategy typically includes version control,or tracking and managing revisions.Each developer can make serveral revisions per day, and the ever-increasing corpus serves simultaneously as repository,project narrative,communication medium,and team and product management tool.Given its pivotal role,version control is most effective when tailored to the working habits and goals of the project team.</p></blockquote>

<p>在一些文本和代码项目中，备份策略具有代表性的包含版本控制，跟踪和管理修正。每个开发者每天都可以做数次修正，同时在库中语料资料不断增长：项目记录、通讯媒介、小组以及产品管理工具。考虑到它的关键角色，当在项目中制定工作习惯和目标时，版本控制是最高效的。</p>

<blockquote><p>A tool that manages and tracks different versions of software or other content is referred to generically as a version control system (VCS),a source code manager (SCM),a revision control system (RCS), and with several other permutations of the words &#8220;revision&#8221;,&#8221;version&#8221;,&#8221;content&#8221;,&#8221;control&#8221;,&#8221;management&#8221; and &#8220;system&#8221;.Although the authors and users of each tool might debate esoterics,each system addresses the same issues:develop and maintain a repository of content,provide access to historical editions of each datum, and record all changes in a log.In this book,the term version control system (VCS) is used to refer generically to any form of revision control system.</p>

<p>This book covers Git,a particularly powerful, flexible, and low-overhead version control tool that makes collaborative development a pleasure.Git was invented by Linus Torvalds to support the development of the Linux Kernel,but it has since proven valuable to a wide range of projects.</p></blockquote>

<h2>The Birth of Git-Git的起源</h2>

<blockquote><p>Often,when there is discord between a tool and a project,the developers simply create a new tool.Indeed,in the world of software,the temptation to create new tools can be deceptively easy and inviting.In the face of many existing version control systems,the decision to create another shouldn&#8217;t be made casually.However,given a critical need,a bit of insight,and a healthy dose of motivation,forging a new tool can be exactly the right course.</p>

<p>Git,affectionately termed &#8220;the information manager from hell&#8221; by its creator is such a tool.Although the precise circumstances and timing of its genesis are shrouded in political wrangling within the Linux Kernel community,there is no doubt that what came from that fireis a well-engineered version control system capable of supporting worldwide development of software on a large scale.</p>

<p>Prior to Git,the Linux Kernel was developed using the commercial BitKeeper VCS,which provided sophisticated operations not ayailable in then-current,free software version control systems such as RCS and CVS.However,when the company that owned BitKeeper placed additional restrictions on its &#8220;free as in beer&#8221; version in the spring of 2005,the Linux community realized that BitKeeper was no longer a viable solution.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
